## Jared Kozar

New York, NY

917-656-1034 | jared.rkozar@gmail.com

Website: www.jaredrkozar.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaredkozar/ | GitHub: https://github.com/jaredrkozar

#### **OBJECTIVE SUMMARY:**

Seeking a position at a company where I can maximize my 2+ years of app development experience using Swift and SwiftUI to contribute to innovative projects that delight and excite users. Strong advocate for building visually appealing products while maintaining excellent code quality and top-tier performance.

#### TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE:

Languages: Swift, UIKit, SwiftUI, React, HTML, CSS, JavaS cript, Object-oriented programming

Programs: Xcode, Git, GitHub, Sketch, Adobe Photoshop

Technologies: MVC, MVVM, Auto Layout, Storyboards, Core Data, Combine, RESTful APIs, AVKit, VisionKit, Core Graphics

#### **EDUCATION:**

University of Hartford, Hartford, CT

August 2019 - May 2023

Dual Major: Bachelor of Science, Computer Science and Bachelor of Arts, Multimedia Web Design

Overall GPA: 3.88, Summa Cum Laude

### **EXPERIENCE:**

## **Technology Leadership Development Program Intern, Travelers Insurance**

June 2022 - August 2022

- Wrote a full stack application using Node and Express to collect data from 4 internal services for debugging user accounts, enhancing efficiency and accuracy in issue resolution
- Collaborated with DevOps engineer to migrate Node.js backend service to a cloud-based architecture using AWS Lambda, removing the need to pull from a developer's local machine
- Designed an easy to use and responsive UI using React and CSS so engineers can easily debug user accounts without having to run a script, which improved employee productivity by 50%

## Computer Science Peer Tutor, University of Hartford

October 2022 - May 2023

- Chosen by the head of CS department to tutor 10 students per week in web development, Java, and data structures, contributing to the academic growth and success of the students who I tutored
- Reviewed course material and helped students develop homework and test-taking strategies that bolstered their academic performance

## CS 220 Data Structures and Algorithms Teaching Assistant, University of Hartford

August 2022 - December 2022

- Attended all classes and held office hours twice a week to assist students who needed clarification on code and concepts taught
  in class, ensuring that students received the support they needed to grasp and apply complex programming principles
  effectively
- Checked student work for completeness, plagiarism and functionality, contributing to a fair and high-quality educational experience

## **PROJECTS:**

#### SimpleNotes (https://github.com/jaredrkozar/SimpleNotes):

March 2022 - Present

- Independently developed an iOS app using SwiftUI in an MVVM architecture to allow users to take notes using their iPhone, iPad, or Mac
- Created a custom drawing engine using bezier paths and Core Graphics to allow drawing, highlighting, and inserting text and straight lines
- Utilized the Google Drive and Dropbox APIs to allow users to upload and download notes and documents to cloud services

# VisionText (https://github.com/jaredrkozar/VisionText)

June 2021 - October 2021

- Created an iOS, iPad, and Mac app with Swift and UIKit in an MVC architecture, and used VisionKit to extract text from any image or PDF, and AVFoundation to read the text aloud at a user customizable speed, pitch and volume
- Implemented Core Data to quickly save, update, sort, and retrieve documents
- Designed a native iPhone, iPad, and Mac UI programmatically, with support for toolbars, multiple windows, and context
  menus to enhance the user experience